<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>About this application</title>
                <author>
                    <persName>
                        <forename>Stephan</forename>
                        <surname>Kurz</surname>
                    </persName>
                </author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher/>
                <availability>
                       <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">
                           <p>The CC BY 4.0 license applies to this document.</p>
                       </licence>
                   </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>About</head>
                <p>
                    The <hi rend="italic">Ministerratsprotokolle der Habsburgermonarchie und Österreich-Ungarns</hi> are a major corpus of governmental documents stemming from the Habsburg Monarchy’s administrative legacy. 
                    Covering nearly sixty years of government, the minutes of the Ministerial Council are one of the few edited resources that on the one hand display the inner workings of the Monarchy’s governments, 
                    and on the other hand a huge data mine stuffed with prosopographic, political, administrative, economic, cultural, and social information in general on the other.<lb/>
                    The minutes are critically edited at the <ref target="https://www.oeaw.ac.at/en/inz/research-units/cultural-heritage/research/minutes-of-the-council-of-ministers-habsburg-monarchy/">INZ</ref> by the research 
                    unit <ref target="https://www.oeaw.ac.at/en/inz/research-units/cultural-heritage/">Cultural Heritage: Biography and Editions</ref> in a <ref target="https://www.oeaw.ac.at/institute/langzeitforschungsprogramm/">long-term research project</ref> of the Austrian Academy of Sciences.<lb/>
                    Citation data for the <hi rend="italic">Ministerratsprotokolle</hi> published in book form are available in BibTeX format <ref target="../data/mrpprint.bib">here</ref>, printed books can be ordered <ref target="https://verlag.oeaw.ac.at/kategorie_225.ahtml">here</ref>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    This demo application has the purpose of showcasing current Digital Humanities research. <lb/>
                    It presents research data from the INZ that has in part been derived from <ref target="https://hw.oeaw.ac.at/ministerrat/">generic XML data of retro-digitized printed books available at https://hw.oeaw.ac.at/ministerrat/</ref>.
                    <list>
                        <item>The <code>listEvent</code> code samples have originally been developed as a use case for a joint paper for the <ref target="https://graz-2019.tei-c.org/">TEI 2019 annual conference in Graz</ref> which discusses the relation between different dated <code>event</code>s and <code>tei:text</code> referencing those.<lb/>
                            <code>listEvent</code> data is <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY 4.0</ref> licenced. We’d be happy if you let us know how you use the data… 
                        </item>
                        <item>TEI data for sample ministerial council sessions include the necessary <code>event</code> and other additional markup. It has been prepared for presentation during the <ref target="https://infoz.ffzg.hr/INFuture/">INFuture 2019</ref> conference.</item>
                        <item>Moreover, we provide sample minutes documents in <ref target="#docx">.docx format</ref>
                        </item>
                        <item>Due to unsolved licencing issues, we are not able to publish <ref target="https://www.tei-c.org/">TEI</ref> derivates of the generic XML data that is available under <ref target="https://verlag.oeaw.ac.at/OpenAccess">"Open Access"</ref> conditions.</item>
                        <item>Reading this text is allowed.</item>
                        <item>Sources for this demo app are available on <ref target="https://www.github.com/skurzinz/mrptestapp/">GitHub</ref>.</item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>Workflow diagram see <ref target="mrpretro.gv.svg">SVG file</ref>.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>